export const BUSINESSMANAGEMENTA2015 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The reward of a shareholder of 21 company is known as",
A: "profit",
B: "dividend",
C: "wages",
D: "salary",
answer: "B. dividend",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A partner who contributes capital bur does not take active part in the running of the business is",
A: "nominal partner",
B: "general partner",
C: "dormant partner",
D: "limited partner",
answer: "C. dormant partner",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The class of people who are affected by the operation of a business enterprise are collectively known as",
A: "volunteers",
B: "committee",
C: "members",
D: "stakeholders",
answer: "D. stakeholders",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following is an advantage of sole proprietorship?",
A: "Quick decision-making",
B: "Large capital",
C: "Employment of experts",
D: "Limited liability",
answer: "B. Large capital",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The process of influencing workers positively to achieve organizational objectives comes under the function of",
A: "planning.",
B: "organizing.",
C: "directing.",
D: "controlling.",
answer: "C. directing.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The stage in decision-making where critical assessment of the available options is carried out is referred to as",
A: "definition of the problem.",
B: "analytical stage of the problem",
C: "gathering of information.",
D: "evaluation of alternatives.",
answer: "D. evaluation of alternatives.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. In a line-and-staff organization. the staff officers are the line officers are the executive and the",
A: "managers.",
B: "employers.",
C: "controllers.",
D: "specialists.",
answer: "D. specialists.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Job instructions take the form of",
A: "horizontal communication.",
B: "upward communication.",
C: "downward communication.",
D: "diagonal communication.",
answer: "C. downward communication",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The management function which is said to be an integral part of all the other functions is",
A: "planning.",
B: "controlling.",
C: "organizing.",
D: "directing.",
answer: "A. planning.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The purpose of creating functional divisions in an organization is to encourage",
A: "centralization.",
B: "Specialization",
C: "Privatization",
D: "decentralization",
answer: "B. specialization.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. When a manager ensures that the different departments of a company work in harmony, he is performing the function of",
A: "directing.",
B: "controlling.",
C: "co-ordinating.",
D: "planning.",
answer: "B. co—ordinating",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The comparison of actual performance with the stated objectives shows which management function?",
A: "Planning",
B: "Organizing",
C: "Directing",
D: "Controlling",
answer: "D. Controlling.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Communication gap exists when",
A: "perceived meaning is different from intended meaning.",
B: "sender and receiver have the same understanding.",
C: "feedback is received promptly.",
D: "it is a two way affair between sender and receiver.",
answer: "A. perceived meaning is different from intended meaning.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Communication is said to be complete when the",
A: "communication is factual.",
B: "intended meaning is received.",
C: "recipient does not understand the message.",
D: "communication is in writing.",
answer: "B. intended meaning is received",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The printer of a computer is an example of",
A: "input device.",
B: "output device.",
C: "processing device.",
D: "scanning device.",
answer: "B. output device",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Computer software refers to",
A: "output unit.",
B: "the instructions that tell the computer what to do.",
C: "the storage unit.",
D: "that part of the computer that is made of plastic.",
answer: "B. the instructions that tell the computer what to do.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. An important rule in the law of contract is that",
A: "principal should always rectify agent’s act.",
B: "all arrangements must be sealed.",
C: "acceptance must he communicated.",
D: "an offer must move from the promise.",
answer: "C. acceptance must he communicated.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A cheque which allows anyone in possession of it to he paid i",
A: "a crossed cheque.",
B: "an open cheque.",
C: "a stale cheque.",
D: "an endorsed cheque.",
answer: "B. an open cheque",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following is not a negotiable instrument?",
A: "Crossed cheque",
B: "Postal order",
C: "Promissory note",
D: "Treasury bill",
answer: "B. Postal order",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following is a duty of an agent?",
A: "Disclose vital business information.",
B: "Act on his own in all cases.",
C: "Withhold account from his principal.",
D: "Have conflict of interest.",
answer: "A. Disclose vital business information.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. A contract that is valid and in which one of the parties to the contract is bound is called",
A: "voidable contract.",
B: "void contract.",
C: "avoidable contract.",
D: "null contract.",
answer: "A. voidable contract",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Demand-pull inflation favours",
A: "pensioners.",
B: "producers.",
C: "depositors.",
D: "creditors.",
answer: "B. producers.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following functions is performed by commercial banks?",
A: "Issuing of currencies.",
B: "Sewing as an agent of payment.",
C: "Regulating activities of other banks.",
D: "Serving as a lender of last resort",
answer: "B. Sewing as an agent of payment",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The aid to trade which deals with the pooling and management of risks is",
A: "communication.",
B: "warehousing.",
C: "transport.",
D: "insurance.",
answer: "D. insurance.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following is an attribute of a good tax system?",
A: "Rigidity",
B: "Transferability",
C: "Divisibility",
D: "Flexibility",
answer: "D. Flexibility",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following is not a source of government revenue?",
A: "Court fines",
B: "Tax refund",
C: "Foreign aid and grants",
D: "Sale of government properly",
answer: "B. Tax refund",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. An advantage of international trade is that it increases",
A: "the cost of domestic firms.",
B: "the power of domestic monopolies.",
C: "international co-operation.",
D: "the import of foreign products.",
answer: "C. international co—operation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The document which enables a consignee to clear goods from the port is",
A: "bill of lading.",
B: "certificate of inspection.",
C: "delivery note.",
D: "proforma invoice.",
answer: "A. bill of lading.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. One of the effects of embargo in international trade is to",
A: "reduce prices.",
B: "reduce imports.",
C: "increase tariffs.",
D: "control production.",
answer: "B. reduce imports.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. One way of reversing a country’s trade deficit is to",
A: "increase export.",
B: "adjust its exchange rate upward.",
C: "revalue its currency upward.",
D: "increase imports.",
answer: "A. increase export.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Balance of payment is the record of",
A: "payments of a country’s imports.",
B: "importation of goods and services.",
C: "a country’s international transactions.",
D: "exportation of goods and services.",
answer: "C. a country’s international transactions",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Which of the following institutions was established to secure financial stability and sustain economic growth among member countries?",
A: "The World Bank",
B: "World Trade Organization",
C: "International Monetary Fund",
D: "International Maritime Organization",
answer: "C. International Monetary Fund",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The main reason for the formation of the Association of South East Asia Nations was to",
A: "introduce different currencies for the member countries.",
B: "promote free trade among member states.",
C: "promote social and cultural integration.",
D: "introduce new taxes to enhance tax revenue.",
answer: "B. promote free trade among member states.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Which of the following business units depend(s) on subventions?",
A: "Public corporations",
B: "Private company",
C: "Sole proprietorship",
D: "Public company",
answer: "A. Public corporations",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. One weapon that management may use to make strike undertaken by workers ineffective is",
A: "boycott.",
B: "picketing.",
C: "corporate campaign.",
D: "lockout",
answer: "D. lockout",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. An advantage of e-commerce is that",
A: "it is possible to examine the product before buying.",
B: "there is personal interaction between sales staff and customers.",
C: "a faulty product may be difficult to return.",
D: "a person need not leave home in order to shop.",
answer: "D. a person need not leave home in order to shop.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. At which stage of the product cycle will the company experience low profits, high production and marketing costs?",
A: "Introduction stage",
B: "Growth stage",
C: "Maturity stage",
D: "Decline stage",
answer: "A. Introduction stage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The use of brand names, trademarks and labelling are all methods of",
A: "target marketing.",
B: "quality control.",
C: "product differentiation.",
D: "market research",
answer: "C. product differentiation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following Is an advantage of outdoor advertising?",
A: "Repeat exposure",
B: "Geographic flexibility",
C: "Audience selectivity",
D: "Low cost",
answer: "A. Repeat exposure",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The technique which seeks to provide employees with different Work experiences by moving them across jobs is known as",
A: "job rotation.",
B: "job analysis.",
C: "job enlargement.",
D: "job enrichment.",
answer: "A. job rotation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The key function of human resource management is to ensure that the organization",
A: "sets product quality standards.",
B: "recruits, selects and retain quality staff.",
C: "bargains for salaries required by labour.",
D: "obtains loans and overdraft for employees.",
answer: "B. recruits, selects and retain quality staff",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following sources of funds is primary to labour unions?",
A: "Donor funds",
B: "Government contribution.",
C: "Membership dues",
D: "Employer’s contribution.",
answer: "C. Membership dues.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The section of a business plan that gives the reader a preview of what the plan contains is",
A: "executive summary.",
B: "mission statement,",
C: "management audit.",
D: "industry summary,",
answer: "B. mission statement",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following stakeholders is a risk bearer in the running of a business?",
A: "Employee",
B: "Debtor",
C: "Entrepreneur",
D: "Underwriter",
answer: "B. Entrepreneur",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Which of the following business entities is funded with tax revenue?",
A: "Private companies",
B: "Public corporations",
C: "Limited partnership",
D: "Co-operative societies",
answer: "B. Public corporations",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. A type of share that confers voting rights but not preferential rights to dividends of a company is",
A: "ordinary share.",
B: "cumulative share.",
C: "bonus share.",
D: "preference share",
answer: "A. ordinary share",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. A speculator at a stock exchange who sells shares in anticipation that prices are about to fall is called a",
A: "broker.",
B: "bull.",
C: "stag.",
D: "bear.",
answer: "D. bear.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. A technique in production in which a fixed number of standard items are produced in group",
A: "job production.",
B: "batch production.",
C: "How production.",
D: "process production.",
answer: "B. batch production",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. A Written statement that identifies the tasks, duties and performance results required in a per job is",
A: "job analysis.",
B: "job description.",
C: "job specification",
D: "job enlargement.",
answer: "B. job description",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The funds contributed by the owners of a business is referred to as",
A: "loan.",
B: "debenture.",
C: "capital.",
D: "mortgage.",
answer: "C. capital.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]